船长！船长！
Who are you？
这是谁啊？
（西班牙 加的斯）
What is this？
这是什么？
Your Majesty，caught him up in a fishing net。A fishing net.
陛下 他是我们用渔网网到的
Sire，he's been telling stories。Stories that…
陛下 他一直在胡言乱语 他说…
We believe he's found a…
我们觉得他找到了…
Ponce de Leon
胡安·庞塞·德莱昂：西班牙人 1513年为寻找不老泉发现佛罗里达 庞赛·德莱昂
Says he found Ponce de Leon's ship.
他说他发现了庞赛·德莱昂的船
- Or sailed on it。- No，I told you，
- 还搭过那艘船 - 不可能 我跟你说过
Ponce de Leon died 200 years ago.
庞赛·德莱昂200年前就死了
Aye，but he died searching for something，didn't he？
是 但他是为了找一样东西才死的 不是吗？
The Fountain of Youth.
不老泉
How soon can you sail？
你船能开多快？
With the tide.
与浪涛齐驱
《加勒比海盗4：惊涛怪浪》
（英格兰 伦敦）
Over here！Lucky heather！
卖幸运花嘞！
Pirate swords！Pirate swords！
处决海盗！
Pirate's execution today。Watch him swing！
今日处决海盗 来看他被吊死吧！
Pirate puppets！
海盗人偶！
Take that，you！
接招吧！
Hurry，Papa，or we'll miss the hanging！
快点 爸爸 不然就看不到绞刑了！
It's not a hanging，dear，it's a trial。The hanging comes this afternoon.
现在还没到绞刑 宝贝 只是审讯 绞刑得等下午
Pirate hanging today！
今天吊死海盗！
Come on。Up you get.
快点 起来
Move along，pirate.
往前走 海盗
Or should I say，「Captain Pirate」？
或者叫“海盗船长”？
Come on。Come on！Up you go.
快点快点！上台阶
Quiet！Order！
肃静！保持秩序！
Quiet！
肃静！
Now appearing before the court，
现在站在法庭上的
the notorious and infamous pirate，pillager，
是声名狼藉、恶名昭著的海盗、强盗
- and highwayman… - Quiet！
- 抢劫犯… - 肃静！
…Captain Jack Sparrow！
杰克·斯派罗船长！
I told you，the name's Gibbs！Joshamee Gibbs！
我说过 我叫吉布斯！杰什米·吉布斯！
- How many times… - Hear ye，hear ye！
- 说了多少次了… - 听好 听好！
Presiding over these trials，
主持这次审讯的是
all rise and attend，the Right Honorable Justice Smith！
各位请起立 欢迎尊敬的史密斯法官！
My dear sir.
阁下
Quiet！
肃静！
Now…
看看…
…what do we have here？
…这是谁呀
Jack？
杰克？
Shut up！
闭嘴！
I don't recognize him.
我没见过他啊
Not necessary。You were saying？
不用打他 你说什么？
Jack Sparrow is not my name.
我不叫杰克·斯派罗
My name is Joshamee Gibbs.
我叫杰什米·吉布斯
Is that so？
真的吗？
- It says Jack Sparrow here。- I told 'em.
- 这里写着杰克·斯派罗 - 我跟他们说了
I'm not Jack Sparrow，who I would be happy to identify to the court
我不是杰克·斯派罗 如果能减轻我罪行的的话
- if it would help my case。- I think that would be a poor defense，
- 我倒很乐意在庭上指认他 - 我看你还是别这样辩护
unless you want to be bludgeoned again like a harp seal.
除非你还想挨棍子
The prisoner claims of being innocent
被告声称自己
to being Jack Sparrow。How do you find？
不是杰克·斯派罗 你们怎么看？
No trial？But aren't we here to examine the evidence…
不审讯吗？可我们还要检查证据…
Foreman，your finding。Guilty？
陪审团主席 你的判决是？有罪？
Guilty verdict means he'll hang.
有罪意味着他要受绞刑？
Hang him！String him up！
绞死他！把他吊死！
- Guilty？- That's not fair！
- 那就有罪 - 这不公平！
Shut it.
闭嘴！
Joshamee Gibbs，the crime of which you've been found guilty of
杰什米·吉布斯 你被判的罪行
is being innocent of being Jack Sparrow.
是“不是杰克·斯派罗”
I hereby commute your sentence，
我在此从轻处理
and order that you be imprisoned for the remainder
判你无期徒刑 在监狱里度过
of your miserable，moribund，mutton-chopped life.
悲惨无助的余生
- What？！- Hang him！
- 什么？！ - 绞死他！
- Hang him！- There.
- 绞死他！ - 退庭
- Balderdash！- String him up！Hang him high！
- 一派胡言！ - 吊死他！绞死他！
Means shall be arranged to transport this prisoner
立即准备把犯人
to the Tower of London.
押到伦敦塔
Thanks very much.
非常感谢
Ta.
谢了
Come on。Get up there.
快点 上去
Get up！
上去！
Hell's teeth。Now we're both headed for prison.
见鬼 现在我俩都要坐牢了
Not to worry。I've paid off the driver.
放心 我买通了车夫
Ten minutes，we'll be outside London Town，horses waiting.
只要十分钟 我们就能出伦敦 马都备好了
Tonight，we make the coast.
今晚就能到海边
Then it's just a matter of finding a ship.
然后找艘船就行了
- All part of the plan，yes？- Exactly.
- 一切都在计划之中 是吧？ - 没错
I arrived in London Town just this morning
今早我到伦敦
to rescue one Joshamee Gibbs from one appointment with the gallows.
来救要上绞刑架的杰什米·吉布斯
Seeing as how you're still alive，
看你还生龙活虎的
I'd say it's all been very successful thus far.
可以说目前我的计划相当成功
What happened to you，Gibbs？
你出了什么事 吉布斯？
I thought you were employed elsewhere or otherwise engaged.
我还以为你上别处干活 或是改行了呢
Aye。But I always listened like a thief for news of the Black Pearl.
我是 但我一直偷偷打听黑珍珠号的消息
Nobody's seen where she might next make port.
没人知道它会在哪儿靠岸
Then，I hear a rumor：
后来我听说
Jack Sparrow's in London with a ship and looking for a crew.
杰克·斯派罗有艘船 正在伦敦招船员
- Am not。- But that's what I heard.
- 我没有 - 但我就是这么听说的
Fact is，you're signing up men tonight.
传闻说 你今晚要签订船员
Pub called The Captain's Daughter.
就在船长千金酒馆
- Am not！- Well，I thought it a bit odd，
- 我没有！ - 我也觉得有点怪
but then，you've never been the most predictable of sorts.
不过你从不按套路出牌
Tell me something.
你说
There is another Jack Sparrow out there sullying my good name？
会不会是有人盗用我杰克·斯派罗的大名？
- An impostor。- Indeed.
- 冒充你 - 没错
But… an impostor with a ship.
但是…这个冒充者有船
And in need of a crew.
还需要船员
Which，as fate would have it，so am I.
真是巧了 我也需要
What about you，Jack？
你怎么样 杰克？
Last I heard，you were hell-bent to find the Fountain of Youth.
之前我听说你发誓要找到不老泉
Any luck？
有眉目了？
Circumstances arose and forced a compelling insight
形势所迫 我不得不把握好
regarding discretion and valor.
何时该谨慎 何时该英勇
- Meaning，you gave up。- I did not.
- 意思是你放弃了 - 我没有
I am just as bent as ever。Hellishly so.
我还是一样坚定 丝毫没变
I shall taste those waters，Master Gibbs。Mark my words.
我一定会喝到那泉水 吉布斯先生 记住我的话
Short trip.
这么快啊
All part of the plan，yes？
一切都在计划中 是吧？
No.
不是
You are Jack Sparrow？
你就是杰克·斯派罗？
There should be a 「Captain」 in there somewhere.
应该加上“船长”
I've heard of you.
我听说过你
And you know who I am.
你也知道我是谁
Face is familiar。Have I threatened you before？
是有点面熟 我惹过你吗？
You are in the presence of George Augustus，Duke of Brunswick-Luneburg，
在你面前的是布伦瑞克-吕内堡公爵 乔治·奥古斯塔斯
Archtreasurer and Prince-elector of the Holy Roman Empire，
神圣罗马帝国的财务大臣和选帝侯
King of Great Britain and Ireland，and of you.
大不列颠及爱尔兰联合王国国王 你的国王
- Doesn't ring a bell。- I am informed
- 没想起来 - 我得知
you have come to London to procure a crew for your ship.
你来伦敦是为了招募船员
Vicious rumor。Not true.
诽谤 没这回事
Then you lied to me when you told me you were Jack Sparrow.
那就是你谎称自己是杰克·斯派罗
I am Jack Sparrow，but I'm not here to procure a crew.
我就是杰克·斯派罗 但我来这不是为了招船员
That is… someone else.
招船员的…另有其人
Someone else named Jack Sparrow.
杰克·斯派罗另有其人
You've brought me the wrong wastrel.
你们抓错人了 这人没用
Find the proper one and dispose of this impostor.
找到对的 把这个冒牌货解决掉
No，wait，wait，wait。Hang on a minute.
不不 等等 等会儿
I'm Jack Sparrow，the one and only.
我就是杰克·斯派罗 货真价实 只此一个
And I am in London.
我确实在伦敦
To procure a crew.
招募船员
To undertake a voyage
准备启程
- to the Fountain… - What？
- 寻找不老泉… - 什么？
Will someone please remove these infernal chains？
谁能把这可恶的手铐拿走？
Come，come.
快点快点
We know you're in possession of a map.
我们知道你有份地图
So confiscate the map，and to the gallows with him！
地图没收 送他上绞架！
Have you a map？
你有地图吗？
- No。- Where is it？
- 没有 - 地图在哪儿？
The truth？I lost it.
想听实话吗？我弄丢了
- Quite recently，in fact。- I have a report.
- 就在刚才 - 我得到情报
The Spanish have located the Fountain of Youth.
西班牙人已经获知不老泉的位置
I will not have some melancholy Spanish monarch，
我可不能让那个多愁善感的西班牙国王
a Catholic，gain eternal life！
那个天主教徒 长生不老！
You do know the way to the Fountain？
你知道怎么去不老泉吧？
Of course I do。Look at me.
当然知道
You could guide an expedition.
你可以率领远征队
With your permission，your heinie，
只要陛下您同意
you will be providing，then，a ship…
给我 呃 一艘船…
…and a crew？
…和船员
And a captain.
还有船长
Afternoon，sire.
午安 陛下
If I may be so bold，why is that man not in chains？
恕我直言 为什么没把那个人拷起来？
He must be manacled at once.
必须立刻把他拷上
At the center of my palace？Hardly.
在我的皇宫中？他跑不了
Hector.
赫克托
How nice to see a fellow pirate make good of himself.
真高兴能看到海盗朋友改邪归正
Pirate？Nay。Privateer.
海盗？不 我是私掠船船长
On a sanctioned mission under the authority and protection of the Crown.
正在执行由王室授权的任务 并受王室保护
As may be，but first，
就算是吧 但是
what has become of my beloved Pearl？
我心爱的黑珍珠怎么样了？
I lost the Pearl as I lost my leg.
我把黑珍珠弄丢了 我的腿也没了！
- Lost the Pearl？- Aye.
- 黑珍珠丢了？ - 对
I defended her mightily enough，but she be sunk nonetheless.
我奋力保护她 但她还是沉了
If that ship be sunk properly，you should be sunk with it.
如果船真的沉了 你该跟她一起沉
Captain Barbossa，each second we tarry，the Spanish outdistance us.
巴博萨船长 我们每拖延一秒钟 西班牙人就领先一步
I have every confidence you will prevail and be rewarded
我有绝对的信心 你定能战胜他们
with the high station you so desire.
获得你渴望的崇高地位
- To serve doth suffice，sire。- You，sir，have stooped.
- 为您不遗余力 陛下 - 船长 你堕落了
Jack，our sands be all but run.
杰克 我们时间不多了
Where's the harm in joining the winning side？
何不加入赢家的队伍？
And you do meet a nicer class of person.
还能结识王公贵族
I understand everything.
我什么都懂了
Except that wig.
除了你那顶假发
He's getting away！Stop him！
他要逃跑！拦下他！
- Head him off！- No！Stop that pirate！
- 拦住他！ - 拦住那个海盗！
Come down！
下来！
- He escaped？- Leave it to me，sire.
- 他跑了？ - 交给我 陛下
Guards！Guards！
守卫！守卫！
- Arms at ready！- Aye，sir！
- 准备武器！ - 遵命 先生！
Find him！
找到他！
Finders keepers！
谁捡归谁！
There！
在那里！
Is that it？
这就完了？
Halt！Stop that carriage！
停车！拦住那辆马车！
Head him off！
拦下他！
Out of the way！
别挡路！
Stop that pirate！
拦住那个海盗！
Move out of the way！
快让开！
Stop that man！
拦住那个人！
Don't let him get away！
别让他逃了！
Fire！
开火！
He's getting away！After him！Stop him！
他逃走了！跟上！拦住他！
After him！
跟上！
Filthy pirate.
肮脏的海盗
Hello，Jackie.
你好啊 小杰
Hello，Dad.
你好 老爸
I heard you're putting together a crew.
我听说你正在招募船员
If enough people keep saying it，it must be true.
人人都这么说的话 那一定是真的了
I heard where you're headed。The Fountain.
我听说你要去不老泉
Have you been there？
你去过吗？
Does this face look like it's been to the Fountain of Youth？
我这老脸像是去过不老泉的样子么？
- Depends on the light。- Son，the Fountain.
- 这儿光线不好 - 儿子 去不老泉
There'll be items required for the profane ritual.
必须准备几件异教仪式的物品
Two chalices.
两只圣杯
- On the map there was a chalice。- Two，silver.
- 地图上是一只 - 两只 银制的
From the Ponce de Leon ship。You'll need both.
在庞赛·德莱昂的船上 两只都要
- For？- The ritual。Don't be a fool，Jackie.
- 用来干嘛？ - 进行仪式 别犯傻 小杰
Find out every detail before you set sail.
起航前要确定每个细节
Oh，set sail。Love to.
我倒是想起航
But for that，I may need a ship.
但我还需要一艘船
Those folk，over there，they have a ship.
那边那些家伙 他们有船
They're signing up sailors right now.
他们正在签订水手
∮ My heart is pierced by Cupid ∮
∮ 爱神之箭射中我心 ∮
∮ I disdain all glittering gold ∮
∮ 金银财宝算什么 ∮
And one last thing，Jackie.
最后一件事 小杰
The Fountain will test you。Mark my words.
不老泉会考验你的 记住我的话
∮ My heart is pierced by Cupid ∮
∮ 爱神之箭射中我心 ∮
∮ I disdain all glittering gold ∮
∮ 金银财宝算什么 ∮
∮ There is nothing can console me ∮
∮ 唯有你能给我慰藉 ∮
∮ But my jolly sailor bold ∮
∮ 勇敢快乐的水手 ∮
I hear you be recruiting a crew.
听说你们在招募船员
Aye。That is，
对 没错
Jack Sparrow be putting together a modest venture.
杰克·斯派罗正在招募优秀船员出海
You got some nerve，ain't ya？
你胆子也太大了吧？
Turning up here dressed like that？
居然穿成这样来这儿？
What are you，some kind of impostor？
你是什么东西 冒牌货？
Have you any idea who I am，mate？
我是谁你还看不出来吗 兄弟？
Oi，muckers！
嘿 伙计们！
There's a bloke here what's forgotten his own name！
这有个家伙把自己名字都忘了！
Lads，I'm sailing with Sparrow.
伙计们 斯派罗签下我了
Who'll buy a sailor a drink？
一起喝两杯吧！
Who's next？
下一位！
Bring us some more of those ones.
再来几瓶酒！
Yeah，make it four.
对 要四瓶！
You've stolen me，and I'm here to take meself back.
你冒充我 我要揭穿你
Stop doing that.
别闹了
Only one person alive knows that move.
知道这步法的只有一个还活着
Always wanted to do that.
早就想这么做了
Hello，Angelica.
好久不见 安吉莉卡
Hello，Jack。Are you impressed？
好久不见 杰克 意外吧？
I think I almost killed you once or twice there.
刚才有几次我差点就杀死你了
I'm touched at this most sincerest form of flattery.
你的甜言蜜语真让我感动
But why？
为什么冒充我？
You were the only pirate I thought I would pass for.
我会假扮的海盗也就你了
That is not a compliment.
这可不算是称赞
Don't worry，Jack。I forgave you a long time ago.
别担心 杰克 我很久之前就原谅你了
- For what？For leaving you？- Recall that I left you.
- 原谅什么？原谅我甩了你？ - 是我甩了你
A gentleman allows a lady to maintain her fictions.
就让你继续幻想吧 谁叫我是绅士呢
Look，Sparrow。As long as my sailors get their money，
听着 斯派罗 只要能拿到钱
they're willing to put up with any number of peculiarities.
水手就愿意忍受任何怪事
There is one peculiarity with which I will not put up with.
有件怪事我就不能忍受
I will be impersonated as 「Captain.」 Nothing less.
我要当“船长” 货真价实的
Well，for that，you need a ship，
那你得有船才行
and as it turns out，I have one.
现在 有船的是我
I could use a ship.
我可以用你这艘
I hear tell you've been to the Fountain.
我听说你去过不老泉
There be a lot of hear-telling going on these days.
这些天谣言满天飞
- The Fountain of Youth。- Dearest Angelica，fret not.
- 就说不老泉 - 亲爱的安吉莉卡 别担心
You still have a few usable years left.
你还得好几年才用得上不老泉呢
Always so charming.
还是这么会说话
You didn't answer me.
你还没回答我
Aye。Regarding the Fountain。Waste of time，really…
啊 不老泉啊 别白费力气了…
Milady，I see unseamanlike fellows of an officious-looking nature.
小姐 有些家伙来找麻烦了
Wretched pirates！Find 'em！Maggots！
该死的海盗！找到他们！这群臭虫！
Friends of yours？
你朋友？
I may have unintentionally slighted some king or other.
我好像不小心得罪了个国王之类的人
Open it！
开门！
- Yeah，you haven't changed。- Implying the need？
- 你真是一点没变 - 你希望我变？
Yes.
当然
Open this door，in the name of His Majesty.
我以国王的名义命令你把门打开
You betrayed me。You seduced me and you used me.
你背弃了我 你勾引我然后利用我
I was innocent of the ways of men.
那时我还是个不谙情事的小姑娘
You demonstrated a lot of technique for someone I supposedly corrupted.
我还真是带坏了一个很有技巧的小姑娘啊
Imminent danger。Here，now，milady！
火烧眉毛了！这边 小姐！
Open it！
开门！
I was ready to take my vows。And you…
我都要发永愿成为修女了 都是你…
What were you doing in a Spanish convent，anyway？
对了 你当时去西班牙修道院干嘛？
Mistook it for a brothel。Honest mistake.
我搞错了 以为那是妓院 真是失误啊
- There he is！- Over there！
- 他在这儿！ - 那边！
We are at a disadvantage.
情况不妙
Speak for yourself。Unlike some who pretend to be，
那是你 我可不像某人
but cannot，in fact，hold a candle to，
还以为自己装得挺像
I am Captain Jack Sparrow.
我才是杰克·斯派罗船长
How can you say I used you？
你怎么能说我利用了你？
You know exactly how.
你自己清楚
I know，but how can you say it？
我知道 但你怎么能说出口呢？
- So，what is it？- What is what？
- 那到底是怎么回事？ - 什么怎么回事？
About the Fountain.
不老泉的事
What do you know？
你都知道些什么？
You don't happen to be in possession
你该不会是恰巧有
of two silver chalices，circa Ponce de Leon？
庞赛·德莱昂的两只银杯吧？
- No。- Thought not.
- 没有 - 我想也没有
- Why？- I hear stories.
- 怎么了？ - 我听到一些说法
Rumors.
可能是谣言
You are，of course，aware of the ritual.
你肯定知道那个仪式
Yes，I am.
我知道
What is it？What is required？
什么仪式？需要什么？
A mermaid，Jack.
一条美人鱼 杰克
There's been a mistake.
你们搞错了
It's a life sentence，not death。Life！
我被判无期 不是死刑 不用死啊！
- Barbossa。- Thank you，gentlemen.
- 巴博萨 - 谢谢诸位先生们
I trust you can tie a noose.
你会绑绞索吧
That's a hard thing，
太不厚道了
forcing a man to twist his own hanging rope.
居然叫我自己绑绳子吊死自己
You must lie in your bed the way you made it.
你要为你的行为付出代价
What's happened to you？
你是怎么了？
- Where be Jack Sparrow？- He escaped.
- 杰克·斯派罗在哪儿？ - 他逃了？
I'm on a tight schedule，Gibbs.
我时间很紧 吉布斯
The HMS Providence sets sail at first light.
皇家神谕号天亮就启航了
If you do not care to watch it hanging here dead，
如果你不想被吊死在这儿
with a mouth full of flies…
满嘴都是苍蝇的话…
…speak now.
…快招
Take me with you。Any point of the compass…
带我走吧 去哪都行…
Take you where，Gibbs？The Fountain？Aye？
带你去哪儿 吉布斯？不老泉 是吗？
Is that where Jack be headed？
那就是杰克要去的地方吧？
Have you anything you can offer me，Gibbs？
你能给我什么好处 吉布斯？
Anything at all？
有么？
Upon me naked word，you'll not see the dawn.
我说一不二 你活不到天亮了
Hand it over.
拿来
- You fool！- I had just enough time
- 你个蠢货！ - 我已经仔细地
to study those infernal circles.
研究了这该死的圆圈
Every route，every destination。All safe… in here.
所有的路线 所有的目的地 都牢牢地记在我脑子里
Welcome back to His Majesty's navy，Master Gibbs.
欢迎加入皇家海军 吉布斯先生
Show a leg，sailor！
起床了 水手！
Aye，sir.
是 长官
What？
啊？
- There's been a horrible mistake。- Keep moving.
- 这是个严重的错误 - 继续走
- I'm not supposed to be here。- Many a man's woken up at sea，
- 我不该在这儿的 - 很多人在船上醒来时
no idea what，when，wherefore or why.
都不知道自己怎么会来这鬼地方的
No memory of the night afore，whence he signed up
也不记得头天晚上为什么要签雇佣协定
and drank away all his bonus money.
还把所有赏钱都买酒喝了
No，no，no。You don't understand，mate.
不不不 你不懂 兄弟
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow。The original。The only.
我是杰克·斯派罗船长 独此一家 如假包换
Scrum，and the pleasure's all mine。Now，keep moving.
我是斯克拉姆 幸会幸会 赶紧走吧
Scrum.
斯克拉姆
Get your elbows in！
把你的胳膊放进来
Why is there a glass coffin？
那为什么有个玻璃棺材？
Do I look like a man in charge？
我看起来像管事的吗？
- Where am I？- 'Scuse me，Captain Sparrow，sir.
- 这是在哪儿？ - 斯派罗船长先生
I be right honored to welcome you aboard
非常荣幸地欢迎您
our world-renowned vessel of infamy，Queen Anne's Revenge.
登上臭名昭著的安妮女王复仇号
Blackbeard.
黑胡子：本名爱德华·蒂奇 世界航海史上最臭名昭彰的海盗之一 嗜好杀人 黑胡子
Work！
干活！
- He's a curious one。- He's been zombiefied.
- 他很古怪 - 他变成僵尸了
What？
什么？
Zombiefied.
僵尸
Blackbeard's doing。All the officers are the same.
黑胡子干的 他的船员都是
Makes 'em more compliant.
这样他们更顺从
And perpetually ill-tempered.
脾气还很暴躁呢
- Come on。Scrub。- Yeah.
- 快点 擦 - 好
Pull！Pull！Pull！
拉！拉！拉！
Five days underway，at least.
出海至少五天了
Aye。You can tell that by the smell of the sea？
是啊 你从海的气味中判断出来的？
Smell of the crew.
是水手的气味
Oi。What did that poor sod do？
哎 那个倒霉鬼犯的什么事儿？
And how can I make sure to not？
我好引以为戒
Him？Churchly fellow.
他？是个教徒
Always going on about the Lord Almighty.
老是说万能的主
Bible-thumper on this ship？
船上的传教士？
A missionary is his story.
以前是
What I heard was he got captured in a raid.
我听说他是一次突袭时被抓来的
Rest of the ship got killed，but not 'im.
船上其他人都被杀了 就剩他
First mate wouldn't let it happen
大副不愿意杀他
on account of his premier standing with the Lord.
因为他信主
A first mate sticking her neck out for some prisoner.
那个女大副以自己的性命担保这个犯人
That you don't see.
稀奇吧
「Her」？First mate is a 「her」？
女大副？大副是个女的？
Back to work！
回去干活！
Steady as she goes.
保持平稳
You are a ruthless，soulless，cross-grained cur.
你这个无情无义、倔强任性的坏蛋
- I told you I had a ship。- No，Blackbeard has a ship，
- 我说了我有船 - 这船是黑胡子的
upon which I am now imprisoned.
而我被困在这了
We can do this，Jack.
我们能做到的 杰克
The Fountain of Youth，like you always wanted.
找到不老泉 你不是一直想么
Blackbeard。Edward Teach。The pirate all pirates fear.
黑胡子 爱德华·蒂奇 所有海盗都惧怕的海盗
Resurrector of the dead in his spare time.
闲着没事还爱弄僵尸
- He will listen to me。- He listens to no one.
- 他会听我的 - 他谁也不听
Maybe to his own daughter？
亲生女儿也不听？
Daughter as in… beget by？
女儿…他有女儿？
Long-lost。Recently found.
失散已久 最近才相认的
Who loves her dear papa with all her soul.
全心全意地爱着她亲爱的老爸
- He bought that？- I sold that.
- 这他也信？ - 我就这么说的
Then it's the Fountain of Youth for him，
所以你找不老泉是为了他
or him and you，not you and me.
或是为了你俩 不是为了我俩
No，Jack，that's the best part.
不 杰克 最重要的是
He will be dead.
他会死的
You'll be handling that part yourself，then？
你会亲手解决他？
There is a prophecy.
有人预言
Maybe you don't believe in the supernatural.
你可能不相信有超自然现象
Oh，no，no。I've seen a thing or two.
哦不不 我经历过几次
The prophecy is this：
预言说
Blackbeard will meet his death within a fortnight
黑胡子两星期内
at the hands of a one-legged man.
就会死在一个独脚男人手上
That's why he needs the Fountain，Jack.
所以他才要找不老泉 杰克
Master Gibbs，short we are a map.
吉布斯先生 我们没有地图
Perhaps you'd be so kind as to provide us an heading.
你总该给指一个方向吧
Be a gem and pour me a gulper.
行行好给我杯酒吧
Nay。We be privateers，not pirates，Master Gibbs.
我们是私掠船船员 可不是海盗 吉布斯先生
And in the king's name，we behave as such.
我们以国王的名义行事
Aye，Captain.
是 船长
Be we on the proper course，Gibbs？
航向对吗 吉布斯？
Aye，it be proper。There's your proof.
航向没问题 那就是证据
The Spaniard.
西班牙人
All hands！Battle stations！Get to windward！
全体船员！准备作战！抢占上风！
- All hands，windward！- Harden up two points！
- 准备作战 抢占上风！ - 调整双点！
- Two points！- Cast loose the cannons！
- 调整双点！ - 装置大炮！
- Gunners，take posts！- Take position！Gunners ready，sir！
- 枪炮手就位！ - 枪炮手就位！枪炮手已就位 长官！
- Out！Thrust！- Await orders.
- 向前！装弹！ - 等待命令！
Steady！
准备！
Guns armed，awaiting orders，sir.
炮已装弹 等待命令 长官
Sir。Orders，sir？
长官 下令吧 长官？
He never so much as turned his head.
他们头都没转
The Fountain is the prize.
找到不老泉才是最终胜利
It appears we be not even worth the time it'd take to sink us.
连击沉我们都是浪费时间
And now we've fallen behind。All hands，make more sail！
我们已经落后了 全体船员 升起风帆！
All hands，more sail！
全体船员 升起风帆！
Ride hard between wind and tide！
乘风破浪前进吧！
The topic，gentlemen，is mutiny.
绅士们 我们要讨论的是 暴动
Mutiny most foul.
最邪恶的 暴动
Aye。I signed up to sail under Jack Sparrow，not some pretender.
我签的是杰克·斯派罗的船 可不是什么冒牌货
And a lady，at that.
还是个女的
And mention was failed to be made of this uncanny crew.
也没提过船上有可怕的僵尸
Make my toes curl，they do.
吓得我头皮直发麻
I got 'em。All of them.
我找到了 所有的都拿来了
- Well done。- Good lad.
- 干得好 - 好兄弟
On to it，then。Blackbeard.
好样的 还有黑胡子
- What are his habits？- Stays mostly to his cabin.
- 他有什么习惯？ - 一直待在船长室
That's right，mostly to his cabin.
没错 一直待在船长室
- Yes，but when he comes out… - He don't really come out.
- 好吧 但他出来的时候… - 他不怎么出来
He must come out sometime.
他总会出来吧
Not really，no.
没见过
Any of you sail with him before？
有人以前跟他出过海吗？
- No，no。- I've never.
- 没人 - 我没有
Definitely not.
绝对没有
- Any of you seen him before？- Not really，no.
- 那有人见过他吗？ - 也没有
Stays to his cabin，no one sailed with him，
一直在船长室 没人跟他出海过
no one's seen him…
没人见过他…
Good news，gentlemen。This is not Blackbeard's ship.
好消息 先生们 这不是黑胡子的船
This is not the Queen Anne's Revenge.
这不是安妮女王复仇号
No，this be the Queen Anne's Revenge，right enough.
这绝对是安妮女王复仇号
How do you know？
你怎么知道？
I've seen the name，on the back of the ship.
我看到了船名 就在船后舷
Gentlemen，sirs，fellow conscriptees…
绅士们 先生们 战友们…
…you have been monstrously deceived.
…你们都被骗了
- We are decepted，then？- Yes.
- 我们被耍了？ - 对
You've nay been informed of a destination.
你们不知道目的地
Death lies before us
等待我们的将是死亡
as we sail for the Fountain of Youth.
因为我们正驶向不老泉
It would be a sorry plight，mates.
我们处境不妙 兄弟们
- Death，for certain。- The garden of darkened souls.
- 完了 死定了 - 那是阴暗灵魂的花园
- Untimely our ends will be。- Unless…
- 我们会死在那里 - 除非…
…we take the ship.
…我们占领这艘船
We take the ship，then。Now！
那就占领这艘船 就现在！
Go on，then.
去吧！
- Help me，shipmates！- Give it to 'em！
- 帮个忙 兄弟们！ - 让他们瞧瞧！
- Wake up！It's ours！- Come on！
- 快起来！我们占领这了！ - 快！
Get up！Off your backside！
起床！下来吧！
- Get off your fannies！- Take it to them，lads！
- 都给我起来！ - 给他们点颜色看看 兄弟们！
Help me！Fight！
一起打吧！
Jack.
杰克
If this is a dream，you can keep the sword and boots on.
如果这是梦的话 你就别摘剑脱鞋了
- If it's not… - It's a dream.
- 如果不是… - 这是梦
No，it's not！
不 这不是梦！
I thought I should give you fair warning，we're taking the ship.
我得好心警告你一声 我们要占领这艘船
Nothing personal.
不是针对你
Think you might be better off if you just…
所以你最好还是…
…stay out of it.
…别插手
Boggit.
真讨厌
Wretch！
混蛋！
You're either with us or against us！
帮我们还是帮他们？
I am not with you，neither am I against you！
我不帮你们 也不帮他们！
Can he do that？
这也行啊？
He's religious。I believe it's required.
他信教嘛 要保持中立
Fight to the bitter end，you cack-handed deck apes！
你们就硬挺吧 一群蠢货！
Take him，men。Tie him down tight！
抓住他 伙计 把他绑起来！
The ship is ours！
船是我们的了！
Gentlemen.
先生们
I be placed in a bewilderment.
我被你们搞糊涂了
There I were，resting，
我正休息得好好的
and upon a sudden，I hear an ungodly row on deck.
突然就听甲板上一阵喧闹
Sailors abandon their posts
水手们未经同意
without orders，without leave.
擅离职守
Men before the mast，
桅杆前的几个人
taking the ship for themselves.
把船占为己有
What be that，First Mate？
这算什么 大副？
- Mutiny，Captain。- Again？
- 是暴动 船长 - 再说一遍？
- Mutiny！- Aye.
- 暴动！ - 没错
Mutiny.
暴动
And what fate befalls mutineers？
暴动者该怎么处置
Now，we know the answer to that，do we not？
大家都知道吧？
Mutineers hang！
暴动者罪当吊死！
Captain，I wish to report a mutiny.
船长 我要向您报告一起暴动
I can name fingers and point names.
我能把他们都指认出来
No need，Mr。Sparrow.
不用了 斯派罗先生
They are sheep。You，their shepherd.
他们只是棋子 你才是带头的
Have I mentioned，sir，what a lovely daughter you have？
您女儿可真漂亮啊 长官
A fitting last sight for a doomed soul.
就当作你生前最后的美景吧
Remember，Father。We need him.
别忘了 父亲 我们需要他
If I don't kill a man every now and then，
我要是不隔三差五杀个人
- they forget who I am。- Coward！
- 他们该忘记我是谁了 - 懦夫！
They do not forget.
他们不会忘记的
Your crew sees you for the miscreant you are.
船员们会记得你是恶棍
A coward，no matter how many you slay.
是个懦夫 不管你杀多少人
Twice in one day，I find myself in a bewilderment.
这是我今天第二次被搞糊涂了
You are not bewildered，you are afraid.
你不是糊涂 你是害怕
You dare not walk the path of righteousness，the way of the light.
你不敢走正义的光明大道
No，sir。The truth is it be much simpler than all that.
你错了 先生 事情远没有你想得那么复杂
- I am a bad man。- That，too.
- 我就是个大恶人 - 我说的也对
I might have to kill you too，catechist.
我应该把你也杀了 传教士
- No！- All Latin blood like her mother.
- 不行！ - 倔脾气跟你母亲一样
Father，I beg you.
父亲 求你了
There I be again，forgetting why the missionary is here.
啊 我差点忘了船上为什么会有传教士
My daughter fears for my soul，or what's left of it.
我女儿担心我残缺不堪的灵魂
You truly wish to save me，my child？
你真的以为能拯救我么 孩子？
Every soul can be saved.
每个灵魂都能得到救赎
Be that true，young cleric？
是真的吗 年轻人？
Yes。Though you I see as a bit of a long shot.
是 虽然拯救你难度很大
Still，I pray for every unfortunate soul on this hell-bound vessel.
我仍会为这诅咒之船上每一个不幸的灵魂祈祷
You disarm me with your faith.
你的信仰说服了我
Eight bells！
八击钟！
Which of you unfortunate souls stood watch？
哪个倒霉鬼值班？
- I did。I stood watch。- Gunner.
- 我 我值班 - 炮手？
You？
是你？
Aye.
是
好吧
The cook.
是厨子
Perfect。Lower the longboat！
很好 把大艇降下去！
Bring her about！
掉头瞄准！
- Why do you do this？- Mutiny。Our laws be clear.
- 为什么要这么做？ - 暴乱嘛 得按规矩来
Our laws allow the Captain to show leniency.
规矩也允许船长宽宏大量
I have given this man a chance to determine his fate，
我已经给了他掌握自己的命运的机会了
a gift not afforded to all.
不是每个人都有这种机会的
Oh，you now.
该你了
Chance to show the worth of your prayers.
借此机会展示下祈祷的力量吧
Pray he be delivered from… evil？
就祈祷他可以摆脱…魔鬼？
Course made！
发射锁定！
Stop。Give that man a chance。Give yourself a…
住手 给他一个机会 也给你自己一个…
You know when I feel closest to our Maker？
知道我何时感觉最接近主吗？
When I see suffering，pain and anguish.
是当我看到苦难、疼痛和绝望之时
That's when the true design of this world is revealed.
那才是主创造世界的真正意图
And I see it revealed when in times of hardship and tragedy，
因为在苦难和悲剧中
kindness and compassion are shown to those in need.
无助的人会得到仁慈和怜悯
Perhaps you should pray for him to be unharmed，yes？
也许你该祈祷他不会受伤 对吗？
- Please，there's still hope… - Again！
- 求你了 还有希望的… - 再来！
I actually have no interest in the Fountain whatsoever，
我其实对不老泉什么的没兴趣
so，if your heart is set，
如果你非要去
you may drop me off anywhere you like.
就随便找地儿让我下船吧
That'll be all，Quartermaster.
退下吧 舵手
Your words surround you like fog and make you hard to see.
你说话云里雾里的 让人看不透
And what of you，the mighty Blackbeard？
那你呢 无所不能的黑胡子？
Beheaded they say。Still，your body swam
听说你被砍了头
three times around your ship，then climbed back onboard.
身体还能围着船游三圈 再爬回甲板
And here you are，running scared.
而你现在 却在仓皇逃命
- Scared。- To the Fountain.
- 逃命 - 逃去不老泉
The Quartermaster sees things before they happen.
那个舵手能预见未来
He has foreseen my death，and so the fates have spoken.
他预言了我的死亡 泄露了天机
The threads of destiny woven.
命运已经注定了
You have a ridiculously high regard for fate，mate.
你也太迷信命运了 伙计
- And you？- Me？
- 那你呢？ - 我？
I'm skeptical of predicting any future… which includes me.
我对所有预言都持怀疑态度…包括关于我自己的
It'd be foolish to battle fate，but I'd be tempted to cheat it.
和命运作对很愚蠢 但我还是要试着反抗
I will reach the Fountain。You will lead me.
我会找到不老泉 你会带我去的
That knife will serve you no better than the mutiny you devised.
那把刀就和你策划暴动一样没用
Mutiny served me well.
暴动很有用
It gained me an audience with you.
能让我见到你
Aye.
是的
To warn you.
我要警告你
Regarding your first mate，
你的大副
who pretends to be persons she is not.
假装成她说的那个人
Do tell.
说
She is not your daughter.
她不是你女儿
You dare to speak thusly of my flesh and blood？
你敢质疑我的亲生骨肉？
Sir，the woman is consummate in the art of deception.
先生 那女人骗人技术登峰造极
I know。As I mostly unwittingly set her on her wicked path.
我知道 是我无意中带她走上这条歪路的
Though I cannot claim credit
虽然我没有证据
for her existing abundance of natural talent.
不过她可是个天生的骗子
Angelica。My beloved daughter，
安吉莉卡 我心爱的女儿
the one true good thing I have done in this life，
我这辈子里唯一一件好事就是能有她
and you claim to be the one who corrupted her？
而你说是你把她带坏的？
Sir，what she is is pure evil.
先生 她纯粹就是个魔鬼
More to be feared than a wild beast.
比野兽还可怕
Hungry wild beast with gnashing teeth.
还是那种长着獠牙的饥饿野兽
Vengeful，hungry from hell beast…
穷凶恶极的野兽…
- Father？- Sweetness！
- 父亲？ - 宝贝！
No need to hurt him，Father.
没必要伤害他 父亲
He will help us。Won't you，Jack？
他会帮我们的 对吧 杰克？
You see？Even now，she attends to your welfare，
你看吧？她还在帮你说话
giving lie to the claims you make of her.
即使你一直在诬陷她
You will lead us to the Fountain。Yes？
你会带我们去不老泉 是吧？
Put another way.
这么说吧
If I do not make it to the Fountain in time…
如果我不能及时找到不老泉…
…neither will you.
…你也别想
I'll have a wee look-see at those charts straight away then，shall I？
我马上就看航海图 行了吧？
Sir.
长官
- Aye？- Captain，sir，
- 嗯？ - 船长大人
I am unhappy to report rumors，sir，
我很抱歉要向您报告些谣言
among the crew，as to our destination.
是船员们说的 关于目的地
Shut your trap and make way.
闭上你的臭嘴 走开
- That's the way of it，then。- No disrespect，sir.
- 就这样吧 - 无意冒犯 长官
What do the men fear？Say it。Speak the words.
他们在怕什么？你说啊
Whitecap Bay.
白浪湾
Aye，Whitecap Bay.
啊 白浪湾啊
And every worthless seaman fears the name，and rightly so，
窝囊废都怕这个名字
though few know why or dare to ask.
虽然不知道有什么好怕的 也没人敢问
Be the stories true？
传说是真的吗？
Say what robs you of your staunch heart，Gibbs，
你在担心什么 吉布斯
or forever leave it to the wider fields of fancy.
不说就当你是胡说八道
Mermaids，Captain.
美人鱼 船长
Aye。Mermaids.
对 美人鱼
Sea ghouls，devil fish，dreadful in hunger for flesh of man.
海上食人者 邪恶的鱼类 嗜好新鲜的人肉
Mermaid waters，that be our path.
我们正是要通过人鱼的海域
Cling to your soul，Gibbs，
把你的灵魂看紧了 吉布斯
as mermaids be given to take the rest…
因为人鱼会把人吃到…
…to the bone.
…只剩骨头
Steady！Steady，men！Find your courage，
冷静！冷静！水手们！拿出勇气
or be ready to purpose your fear！
战胜恐惧！
Save yourselves！
还是逃吧！
- Man overboard！- Nay！A deserter.
- 水手落水了！ - 不！是逃兵落水
- Come about。- Nay！
- 掉头 - 不！
Gentlemen，I shall not ask any more of any man than what
先生们 我不会勉强你们做你们办不到的事
that man can deliver，but I do ask this：Are we not king's men？
但我要问问你们：我们是不是皇家海军？
Aye.
是
- On the king's mission？- Aye.
- 执行的是不是皇家任务？ - 是
I did not note any fear in the eyes of the Spanish as they passed us by.
那些超过我们的西班牙人 眼里可没有任何恐惧
- Are we not king's men？- Aye！
- 我们是不是皇家海军？ - 是！
Aye！Hands all off，and bear away！
好！全体就位！改变航向！
Stave on ahead to Whitecap Bay！
目标直指白浪湾！
Bear on，Whitecap Bay！
航向 白浪湾！
Come.
来吧
Little drink？
喝两杯
Wine，music，candlelight.
美酒 音乐 烛光
I think we've traveled down this road before，Jack.
这感觉似曾相识啊 杰克
Yes，we have.
对 没错
I remember it well.
我记得很清楚
Winding，twisting and turning，gyrating，writhing.
缠绕 扭动 翻转 回旋 翻滚
Incessant writhing.
不停的翻滚
Do you recall Saint Dominique？
还记得圣多米尼克吗？
La Martinique.
马提尼克岛
I tried to kill you in Saint Dominique.
在圣多米尼克我想杀了你
Either or.
可你没有
Hardly appropriate for a first mate.
杀掉初恋情人实在是不合适
Was I the first？I've often wondered.
我是你的初恋吗？我常常在想
You can be so charming when you want something，Jack.
你想要的样子是如此迷人 杰克
The trick is finding out what.
关键是你想要什么
The truth，then，is it？
真相？
Blackbeard has served his purpose.
黑胡子达到了他的目的
You and I can go to the Fountain together，
我们可以一起去不老泉
where we shall bathe one another in equal shares of fame
一起沐浴 一起享受名誉
and other assorted debaucheries.
纵情肆意
And I'll tell you the ritual of the Fountain.
我会告诉你不老泉的仪式
Yes。The profane ritual.
是的 邪恶的异教仪式
Can I trust you，Jack？
我能信任你吗 杰克？
- I need you on my side。- Oh，my dearest Angelica.
- 我需要你帮我 - 哦 亲爱的安吉莉卡
You and I are as thick as thieves，love.
我们是一条贼船上的亲密恋人
Tell me the rules.
告诉我规则吧
Water from the Fountain of Youth.
不老泉的水
The shimmering tear of a mermaid.
新鲜的人鱼眼泪
The silver chalices of Ponce de Leon.
庞赛·德莱昂的银杯
With these items…
有了这些…
- Yes？- With these items，
- 怎样？ - 有了这些
you may take all the years of life from another，Jack.
你就可以夺走另一个人的寿命 杰克
You know what that means.
你知道这意味着什么
We cannot go alone，you and I.
我们不能单独去 不能只有你和我
The ritual requires a victim.
仪式需要一个祭品
- That is unfortunate。- Yes，it is.
- 真不幸 - 是啊
I find my desire for the Fountain greatly lessened.
我发现对不老泉越来越没兴趣了
But there is something onboard you do want.
但这船上有你最想要的东西
What about Blackbeard？
黑胡子呢？
He's in the chart room。We'll have to be quick.
在航海图室 我们动作要快
He keeps each ship as a prize.
他把抢来的每艘船都留作战利品
You help me，and I promise you your pick.
你帮我 我就让你挑一艘
Though I think I know the one you will choose.
我也知道你会挑哪艘
The Black Pearl in a bottle？
黑珍珠号在瓶子里？
Why is the Black Pearl in a bottle？
黑珍珠号怎么会在瓶子里？
He's even more annoying in miniature.
这猴子变成模型更招人烦了
- Do we have a deal，Jack？- Angelica，I know you.
- 说定了 杰克？ - 安吉莉卡 我了解你
You are not going to steal the life of some innocent man.
你不会夺走无辜的人的性命的
What about the one-legged man？
那个独腿的人怎么样？
I need years，Jack.
我需要寿命 杰克
Not for me。For my father.
不是为我 是为我父亲
I am truly the daughter of Blackbeard.
我真的是黑胡子的女儿
You've fallen for your own con，love.
你入戏太深了 亲爱的
No，he is my father.
没有 他真是我父亲
The lies I told you were not lies.
我跟你说的谎话其实不是谎话
You lied to me by telling me the truth？
你说真话却骗我是谎话？
- Yes。- That's very good.
- 是 - 真厉害
- May I use that？- I'm sure you will，anyway.
- 我能用这招吗？ - 你肯定会用的
Of course I will.
我当然会
So，will you not give up this quest？
所以你不会放弃这次冒险的
I want a father，Jack。I haven't had one.
我想有个父亲 我从没有过
Angelica，your father，Blackbeard…
安吉莉卡 你父亲 黑胡子…
…he is evil，
…他非常邪恶
and he will kill you given the chance.
需要的他连你也杀
- He cannot be saved。- And who are you to set
- 他不可能得到救赎的 - 你凭什么规定
the limits on redemption？
救赎的界限？
You stole years of my life，Jack。You owe me.
你耽误了我的大好时光 杰克 你欠我的
And you are en route to getting yourself killed，
你是在自寻死路
and I am not inclined to stand by and watch.
我不想袖手旁观
Whitecap Bay！
白浪湾！
All hands on deck！Set to the longboats！
全体船员到甲板上集合！ 准备上大艇！
Lay 'em out flat！
把网摊平！
No tangles。Make 'em look pretty for our dainty guests.
不要缠成一团 要漂漂亮亮地迎接我们美丽的客人
We're gonna need light。A lot of light.
我们需要亮光 很亮的光
Come！
过来！
Smell that？Whale oil。Stuff burns like a miracle from God.
闻到了吗？是鲸鱼油 特别好烧
- Can you make it work？- Made by the English.
- 能点起亮吗？ - 英国佬建的
Let's not get our hopes up.
希望不大
The old moon in the arms of the new one.
月牙环抱阴影
First of the summer.
夏季的第一天
Perfect for hunting a mermaid's tear.
最适合收集人鱼眼泪了
We're doomed。They be drawn to man-made light.
我们完了 他们会被灯光引来的
- Sharks？- Worse than sharks，boy.
- 鲨鱼么？ - 比那糟多了 孩子
There'll be mermaids upon us within the hour，
一小时内人鱼就找到这儿
you mark my words。And we're the bait.
相信我 我们会被吃掉的
I heard it said a kiss from a mermaid protects a sailor from drowning.
我听说人鱼的吻可以让水手不会淹死
Don't be a fool！Mermaids are all female，son，
别傻了！人鱼都是母的 孩子
and lovely as a dream of heaven.
美得像天仙一样
But when it comes time to churn butter，so to speak，
但是一到吃饭的时候
they snatch a sailor out of a boat
她们会把水手从船里拖出来
or off the deck of a ship，have their way，
拖下甲板
and then the sailors are pulled to bottom and drowned and eaten.
先拉到海底淹死 然后吃掉
Or，sometimes，the other way around.
有时候是先吃再淹死
- Sing。- What？
- 唱歌 - 什么？
They like to hear singing.
她们喜欢听人唱歌
∮ My name is Maria ∮
∮ 我名叫玛利亚 ∮
∮ A merchant's daughter fair ∮
∮ 商人的美丽女儿 ∮
- Louder。- ∮ And I have left my parents ∮
- 大点声 - ∮ 我已离开了父母 ∮
∮ And 3，000 pounds a year ∮
∮ 每年能赚3000磅 ∮
∮ My heart is pierced by Cupid ∮
∮ 爱神之箭射中我心 ∮
∮ I disdain all glittering gold ∮
∮ 金银财宝算什么 ∮
∮ There is nothing can console me ∮
∮ 唯有你能给我慰藉 ∮
∮ But my jolly sailor bold ∮
∮ 勇敢快乐的水手 ∮
∮ My heart is pierced by Cupid ∮
∮ 爱神之箭射中我心 ∮
∮ I disdain all glittering gold ∮
∮ 金银财宝算什么 ∮
∮ There is nothing can console me ∮
∮ 唯有你能给我慰藉 ∮
∮ But my jolly sailor bold ∮
∮ 勇敢快乐的水手 ∮
Lord save me.
我的天啊
Man，look。Look there.
快看 看那儿
You'll scare her off！
你会把她吓走的！
Aye，and good riddance！
那最好！
Can you talk？
你会说话吗？
Yes.
会
You're beautiful.
你真美
- Are you the one who sings？- Aye.
- 刚才是你在唱歌吗？ - 是
Are you my jolly sailor bold？
你是我勇敢快乐的水手吗？
- Aye，that I be。- Scrum，comport yourself！
- 是 我是 - 斯克拉姆 控制！
Boys！There ain't much been given to me
伙计们！我短暂悲惨的一生中
in my brief，miserable life，there's the truth in it.
没得到过什么 这是实话
But，by God，I'll have it said
现在 上帝说
that Scrum had himself a kiss from a proper mermaid！
斯克拉姆可以吻一下美丽的人鱼！
∮ My heart is pierced by Cupid ∮
∮ 爱神之箭射中我心 ∮
∮ I disdain all glittering gold ∮
∮ 金银财宝算什么 ∮
∮ There is nothing can console me ∮
∮ 唯有你能给我慰藉 ∮
∮ But my jolly sailor bold ∮
∮ 勇敢快乐的水手 ∮
∮ Come all ye pretty fair maids ∮
∮ 来吧 美丽的少女 ∮
∮ Whoever you may be ∮
∮ 无论你是谁 ∮
∮ Who love a jolly sailor bold ∮
∮ 只要你爱勇敢快乐的水手 ∮
∮ That ploughs the raging sea ∮
∮ 他能劈开大海的怒涛 ∮
∮ My heart is pierced by Cupid ∮
∮ 爱神之箭射中我心 ∮
∮ I disdain all glittering gold ∮
∮ 金银财宝算什么 ∮
∮ There is nothing can console me ∮
∮ 唯有你能给我慰藉 ∮
∮ But my jolly sailor bold ∮
∮ 勇敢快乐的水手 ∮
∮ My heart is pierced by Cupid ∮
∮ 爱神之箭射中我心 ∮
∮ I disdain all glittering gold ∮
∮ 金银财宝算什么 ∮
∮ There is nothing can console me ∮
∮ 唯有你能给我慰藉 ∮
∮ But my jolly sailor bold ∮
∮ 勇敢快乐的水手 ∮
Out upon it！It has begun！
出现了！已经打上了！
Light 'em up！
点火！
Muster your courage！Drive 'em to shore！
鼓起勇气！赶她们上岸！
Nets into the water！Quickly！
撒网！快！
Retreat，all，to land！For your lives！
撤退！想活命就快上岸！
Retreat，I say！
撤退！快！
Cowards！Back in the water！
懦夫！回水里去！
There be no refuge on land！On my word！
岸上没地方避难！听我的话！
We got one！
抓到一个！
I'm in love！
我恋爱了！
Check the wounded！
检查受伤的人鱼！
See if you can find one mermaid still alive！
看看还有没有活的！
Come，give a hand！
过来 帮个忙！
Well done，sailor.
干得好 水手
Did everyone see that？
大家看到我跳了吗？
Because I will not be doing it again.
我可再也不跳了喔
Back to the ship。We head for a protected cove。Now.
回船上去 我们要驶到安全的港湾
- Lord。Is that？- Mermaid.
- 上帝 那是？ - 美人鱼
- Give up this madness now。- I cannot.
- 放弃这疯狂的任务吧 - 不行
Ever walk on the beach，
你走在沙滩上时
look back and see your footsteps in the sand？
会回头看留下的两排脚印么？
It's like that，except the footsteps lie before me.
已经到这份儿上 不过我们被人捷足先登了
- Footstep，actually。- Whitecap Bay，sir.
- 你只有一排脚印 - 白浪湾 长官
We must hasten.
我们要加快速度
We travel by foot。Gibbs，I require a heading.
我们步行 吉布斯 你带路
- But，sir，the men。- They be dead already.
- 可是长官 那些人 - 他们已经死了
- They don't sound dead。- Oh，is that so？
- 可他们还在叫喊 - 哦？是吗？
Well，I hear nothing but seagulls nesting.
我可什么都没听到 只有海鸥在叫
What is it that you hear，Mr。Groves？
你听到什么了 格罗夫斯先生？
Seagulls… nesting.
海鸥…在叫
- Nothing more。- Heading，Gibbs？
- 没了 - 领路 吉布斯
My God.
老天啊
Your head or my heading.
领路 不然就领死
I'll have me one or t'other，I don't care which.
哪个我都无所谓
All hands，forward！
所有人员 前进！
- It's to you now，Sparrow。- Was that really necessary？
- 该你了 斯派罗 - 有必要这样吗？
Best you not know the exact whereabouts of my ship.
最好不让你知道船的位置
- I be a cautious man。- So be I.
- 我可是很谨慎的 - 我也是
What I want first…
我最想要的…
…is Ponce De Leon's ship.
…是庞赛·莱昂德的船
Why is it we've got to bring her along？
干嘛要一路带着她？
Because tears don't keep。We need them fresh.
因为眼泪没法保存 得要新鲜的
What is the ritual again？
那个仪式需要什么来着？
Water from the Fountain and a mermaid's tear？
不老泉的水和人鱼的眼泪？
And two silver chalices.
还有两只银杯
One cup with a tear，one without.
一只装人鱼眼泪 一只不装
So，one with a tear and water in both？
就是说 一只既装眼泪又装泉水？
Quite complicated，is it not？
好复杂啊
Both get water。One gets a tear.
两只都装泉水 一只加眼泪
The person who drinks the water with the tear
喝下有眼泪那杯水的人
gets all the years of life from the other.
可以得到另一个人的全部寿命
How many years？
多少年？
All the years that they have lived，
所有已经活过的
and they could have lived，if fate had been kinder.
和剩下没活的寿命 要是他寿命长的话
Clergyman.
传教士
On the off chance that this does not go well for me，
万一我有什么不测
I would like it noted here and now
你想现在就加入
that I am fully prepared to believe in whatever I must，
个随便什么教
so that I may be welcomed into that place
好让我也能去那种
where all the goody-goodies get to go。Savvy？
伪教徒去的地方 懂了吗？
We have a word for that，Jack。You can convert.
我们有专门的说法 杰克 叫皈依
I was thinking more of an as-needed basis.
我觉得还用不着皈依
Quartermaster！
舵手！
- Aye？- She cannot breathe！
- 怎么了？ - 她不能呼吸了！
- She has water。- She needs air！
- 不是有水吗 - 她需要空气！
- Open this。- She will escape.
- 打开 - 她会逃走的
- You're killing her。- I support the missionary's position.
- 她会死的 - 我与传教士立场一致
See？
看到了？
Onward.
前进
Just as I thought。Not this way！
和我想的一样 走错了！
This is the way，isn't it？
就是这条道 没错啊？
'Course it is，but we should go around to the east.
是没错 但是我们得从东边绕道
That would take us out of the path of the chalices.
那就偏离去圣杯的路了
- Well，then we'll circle back。- There is no time.
- 我们会绕回来的 - 没时间绕了
You're the one who insisted on bringing the bloody mermaid.
是你坚持要带那麻烦的人鱼的
- Well，the mutiny didn't help。- You walk like a girl.
- 有本事你再暴动啊 - 走路还扭扭的
- You would know。- Someone must go.
- 你才扭扭的 - 必须有人去
You mean split up？
你是说分头走？
You mean jump？This I cannot wait to see.
你是说跳崖？我等不及看好戏了
Sparrow will go。Find the ship，retrieve the chalices.
斯派罗去吧 找到船 带回圣杯
Sparrow？What makes you think he will come back？
斯派罗？你怎么确保他会回来？
Yes，what makes you think he will come back？
就是 你怎么确保他会回来？
We cannot trust him，Father。I'll go.
他不可信 父亲 我去吧
She'll go.
她要去
How much farther to the Fountain？
不老泉还有多远？
I'm running out of time.
我时间不多了
About a day's march north，following that river，
向北再走一天 沿着那条河
you'll get to a series of pools。Then you're close.
走到有一群小湖泊的地方 就不远了
You will go.
你去
I was sure it would come to this.
我就知道会这样
You know that feeling you get sometimes when you're standing in a high place？
听说有人站在高处
Sudden urge to jump？
会有想跳的冲动？
I don't have it.
我就没那种冲动
I need those chalices.
我需要圣杯
Shoot。Save me the bother of the fall.
开枪吧 省得我纠结跳不跳崖
You will go。You will return…
跳下去 然后回来…
…or I will kill her.
…不然我就杀了她
You won't kill your own daughter.
你不会杀亲生女儿的
Quartermaster，get me six more pistols，
舵手 给我六把手枪
remove the shot from all but two，
四把卸掉子弹 两把上膛
but do not tell me which two.
别告诉我是哪两把
You get to choose，Mr。Sparrow.
你来选 斯派罗先生
No.
不是它
- Yes。- You're sure？
- 这把 - 确定？
'Course I am.
当然
Again.
再选
Please，they're not even loaded.
拜托 这些都没装子弹
Again.
再选
If you're so keen on killing her，
如果你这么想杀她
- why don't you just let her jump？- What？
- 干嘛不直接让她跳？ - 什么？
If you jump and die，
如果你跳下去摔死了
then she will have her chance.
就让她跳
Again.
再来
Oi…
喂…
…if I jump，will I survive？
…我跳下去 还能活吗？
The doll.
巫毒娃娃
- Yes，now you will survive。- This is nonsense！I'm going！
- 能 你能活 - 真是胡闹！我跳！
Wet。Wet again.
湿透了 又湿透了
We go on。Due north to the Fountain.
我们继续 向北走到不老泉
Well played，Father.
合作愉快 父亲
You knew which guns were loaded，right？
你知道哪把枪有子弹吧？
Of course，my love.
当然 宝贝
Be nice to have a map about now.
要是有地图就好了
Or a ship.
有船也行啊
Stop！Hold very still.
站住！千万别动！
Ye dare not let it touch your skin.
别让它碰到你的皮肤
What？What be wrong with an older man having a hobby？
怎么了？老男人就不能有嗜好了？
What are you stopping for，eh？Push on！
还愣着干嘛啊？快走！
- Push on！- You can sleep when you're dead.
- 快走！ - 等你死了再睡不迟
Push on！
快走！
Fortune continues to favor us.
命运一直眷顾我们
The Santiago.
圣地亚哥号
Famously captained by Ponce de Leno.
著名的庞赛·德莱昂船长的船
There's no one there.
没人啊
Right，then.
好吧
We must not stop.
我们不能停
You will walk.
你自己走
I cannot.
我不会
Walk or die.
不走就死
Put your arms around me.
胳膊搭着我
- I do not ask for help。- But you need it.
- 我没叫人帮忙 - 但你需要
- We're in a hurry，yes？- Do not fall behind.
- 不是赶时间么？ - 别掉队
Hold here 'til I say！
原地休息！
Such beauty.
这么美丽
Surely you're one of God's own creations，
一定是上帝亲手创造的杰作
and not a descendant of those dark creatures
不像那些连方舟
who found no refuge on the Ark.
都不容的邪恶生物
Such beauty…
这么美丽…
…and yet deadly.
却又致命…
- Deadly？No。- You attacked me.
- 致命？才不是 - 你袭击我
No。You are different.
我没有 你不一样
Different？
不一样？
Are you not？You protect.
难道不是吗？你会保护
Did you？
是你？
You pushed me down out of the way.
是你把我推开的
- You see the Fountain？- No，but we are close.
- 看到不老泉了吗？ - 还没 不过已经近了
Bring the creature。Cover its head.
带上那个东西 罩住它的头
She has a name！
她有名字！
Pray tell.
愿闻其详
She is Syrena.
她叫瑟琳娜
Ponce de Leon.
庞赛·德莱昂
If 40 pirates dreamt 40 nights of treasure，
就算40个海盗做40个发财梦
it would not match the contents of this room.
也梦不到这屋里这么多的宝藏
You.
是你
- You。- No…
- 是你 - 不…
- …you。- I was here first.
- 是你 - 我先来的
- You，why are you here？- Blackbeard sent me.
- 你 怎么会是你？ - 黑胡子送我来的
- Why are you？- Silver chalices
- 你呢？ - 为尊敬的陛下
- for my royal liege。- Oh，please.
- 取回圣杯 - 拜托
Back，back！We have to balance it out！
退后 退后！要保持平衡！
The whole ship will slide！
否则整艘船都会滑下去的！
Right，then.
好吧
What if we each choose an item of approximately equal weight？
不如我们各拿一个差不多重的东西？
Put it back！
放回去！
We touch nothing！
什么也别动！
What about that？
那个呢？
The chalices.
圣杯
Oi！Why do you get to look first？
喂！凭什么你先看啊？
Fine，then.
好吧
- Together。- Together.
- 一起 - 一起
Rocks.
石头
The Spanish.
是西班牙人
They're ahead of us，mate.
被他们抢先了
I shall have a look at that map。If it's what I fear…
我得看看那地图 就怕他们…
I wonder why they left this behind.
奇怪 他们居然把这个留下了
Don't touch the map.
别碰地图
They know the path，
他们知道路线
but I can also see where they'll most likely make camp.
但我也知道他们会在哪里扎营
Jack！
杰克！
Gibbs，I was just on me way to break you out of jail.
吉布斯 我正要去监狱救你
You stole my map.
你偷了我的地图
Right。Best be started.
好了 该走了
Ol？
好嘞
Mermaids.
人鱼
Careful，these pools run deep.
小心点 这些湖很深
If she escapes，all is lost。Quartermaster.
她要是逃了 什么都白搭 舵手
Look。Look！
看 给我看！
Staked out to die，to dry in the sun.
被柱子钉死 被阳光晒干
Only half in the water。Not enough to live，
一半身子在水里 活不了
but just enough to make the dying slow.
却会受尽折磨慢慢地死去
Think on it.
想想吧
Your people，murdered，harvested for their tears.
人类 为了收集泪水 杀死你的同胞
Syrena，won't you cry？
瑟琳娜 你就不想哭吗？
All die，even you.
谁都会死的
- Soon，I hear。- Listen…
- 听说你也快了 - 听…
Listen.
你听
Can you not hear your sisters scream？
听到你姐妹们的尖叫了吗？
Do you not hear them？
听到了吗？
We need but one tear.
我们只要一滴眼泪
Vile creature！
卑鄙的生物！
- Chop off her fingers，one by one！- Choke her！
- 剁掉她的手指 一根一根剁！ - 抽死她！
Cut out the tears from behind the eyes！
把眼泪给从她眼睛里挖出来！
Where's your voice in this？
你怎么不说话了？
Maybe she'll have a change of heart when the sun rises.
也许日出后她会改主意
Oh，aye，she will burn，but I cannot wait for the sun.
没错 她会被晒死 但我等不及了
Perhaps we should build a fire.
也许我们该生一堆火
- No。- Do not contest me，cleric.
- 不行 - 不要挑战我 传教士
- You will not torture her。- We need only one tear.
- 你不能折磨她 - 我们只要一滴眼泪
I will tear every scale from her body one by one if I see fit.
需要的话 我会把她身上的鱼鳞一片片刮下来
If that displeases you，go pray.
你不愿意就去祷告好了
I was wrong。Not every soul can be saved。Yours cannot.
我错了 不是所有灵魂都能得到救赎 你就不能
Behold，gentlemen，a man formerly of faith.
看吧 各位 信仰多不靠谱
That vile creature，as you call her，is worth a hundred of you.
你口中的卑劣的生物 胜过你一百倍
Oh，you care for her？
哦？你很在意她？
You fancy her.
你喜欢她
And do not deny what is clear to my eyes.
不要否认 我看的清清楚楚
Question is…
问题是…
…does she fancy you？
…她也喜欢你吗？
By God，she does。We are in luck！
上帝 她喜欢 我们走运了！
Bring forth a tear…
流一滴泪…
…or witness the death of this poor soul.
…不然他就会死
Syrena，if you could manage a tear，
瑟琳娜 如果你能流一滴泪
I would be grateful.
我会非常感谢
Sadness，yes，
悲伤 没错
- but no sorrow… yet。- Not by your hand，Father！
- 但痛苦…还不够 - 你不能杀人 父亲！
Time and tide wait for none。Quartermaster.
时间和潮汐都不等人 舵手
Aye，mermaids are tough.
喔 多坚强的人鱼
The lot of them.
都一个德行
Tie her up like the others。And get rid of this.
把她绑起来 把尸体丢掉
- You are confident？- Yes.
- 你有把握？ - 是
I am a woman。So is she.
我是女人 我了解女人
What's your play，Jack？Throwing in with Barbossa.
你怎么想的 杰克？居然和巴博萨合作
There is a girl…
有个女孩…
…a female… of the opposite sex.
…女人…异性
- When is there not？- Perhaps I should say 「damsel.」
- 你什么时候缺过女人了？ - 我是说“少女”
You're rescuing a damsel？Well，there's a first.
你要英雄救美？凡事都有第一次嘛
Yes，but it's just that I may have caused said damsel
是 不过我很久以前
- some manner of harm many moons ago。- Out with it.
- 好像伤害了这位少女 - 直说吧
Gibbs，this is the woman from Seville.
吉布斯 她是塞维利亚来的
Ah，you pretended to love her，then you left her and broke her heart.
哦 你假装爱她 然后把她甩了 伤了人家的心
Worse。I may have had，briefly，mind you…
更糟 我可能 有一点点…
- …stirrings。- Stirrings？
- 心动… - 心动？
- Stirrings。- What？Like feelings，you mean？
- 是心动 - 什么？你是说有感觉？
No，no，no。Not quite all the way to feelings。More like…
不不不 也不算有感觉 就是…
All right，feelings，damn you.
好吧 是有感觉 该死
And you left her still。That's low.
但你还是离开了她 真卑鄙
Thank you.
承蒙夸奖
Stealth over force.
不能硬来
I'll take it from here on account of your condition.
让我来吧 你不太方便
You don't have termites，do you？
腿里没长白蚁吧？
I appreciate your concern，Jack，
多谢关心 杰克
but I'll be keeping you company all the same.
但我得一直跟着你
Hold here，Lieutenant Commander。Wait for my signal.
少校 你留在这等我信号
There。That one。That be the leader.
那边那个 一定是首领
Make note of his tent because that's where…
记住他的帐篷 因为…
No，wait。By God，that must be them right there.
等等 上帝啊 那一定是圣杯
Your sword smells funny.
你的剑有怪味道
Aye。Poison from the innards of poisonous toads.
没错 淬了箭毒蛙内脏的毒液
Just a scratch，you're a dead man in minutes.
只要被划一下 几分钟准挂
Would you mind pointing it the other way？
你能不能别拿它对着我？
I don't like toads.
我不喜欢蟾蜍
- What are you doing？- Planning an escape route.
- 你在干嘛？ - 策划逃跑线路
- Isn't that how you do it？- Yes.
- 你不总这样干么？ - 没错
Or sometimes I just… improvise.
有时候我也…即兴发挥
Now what？
现在怎么办？
We stroll out，slow and steady.
我们溜达出去 淡定不要急
Just like we belong.
别太见外
- I'm sorry，Syrena。- Philip，you're alive.
- 对不起 瑟琳娜 - 菲利普 你还活着
- Yes。- You came for me.
- 是的 - 你来救我
Why？
为什么？
You're different，are you not？
你不一样 不是吗？
Do you know not of kindness？Compassion？
你懂得仁慈和怜悯
Tears of sorrow，never.
悲伤的眼泪太难搞
Mermaids be too tough for that.
人鱼都太顽强了
But tears of joy…
但快乐的眼泪…
They say these be the more potent anyway.
听说这种眼泪更有效
Syrena，on my word，I had no part in this.
瑟琳娜 我发誓 我不知情
Let her go。You don't need her now.
放她走吧 你已经不需要她了
Let her go？No.
放她走？不行
Secure her bonds。We leave her with her own.
把她绑紧 让她自生自灭吧
How's that escape route working？
你的逃跑路线呢？
Here's your chance to improvise.
轮到你即兴发挥了
I'm attempting it.
我正在努力
I might be able to get a hand loose.
只要弄松一只手
Oh，you got a knife。That's very good.
哦 你有把刀 太好了
Better.
比刀更好
I want one of those.
我也要
Here's to revenge。Sweet and clear.
你是来复仇的吧
- Revenge？- Come，come，Hector.
- 复仇？ - 少来了 赫克托
If you wanted the chalices，
如果你想要圣杯
you'd seen they were missing and gone.
你早就会发现它们不见了
You were lying in wait，for Blackbeard.
你在船上是想等黑胡子
King George。Privateer。Wig.
乔治国王 私掠船 假发
Cheap theatrical facade.
太小儿科了
- I'm not buying it。- You weren't there that night.
- 可骗不过我 - 那晚你不在
- When the Pearl was lost？- Taken，not lost.
- 弄丢黑珍珠 那晚？ - 是被抢 不是弄丢
We were off the coast of Hispaniola when we came under attack.
我们在伊斯帕尼奥拉海岸遭到突袭
No provocation nor warning nor offer of parley.
没有原因 没有警告 也没人来谈判
We were peppered with cannon fire.
我们遭到炮火的猛烈攻击
And then the sea beneath the Pearl began to roil.
然后 黑珍珠周围的海水开始翻滚
The Pearl was pitching and yawing violently.
黑珍珠号在海浪中颠簸 剧烈地摇晃
Every plank，every rail，
每块木板 每条横栏
every spar，all at once，began to creak.
每根帆柱 突然都开始咯吱作响
The rigging had come to life.
绳索好像活了过来
Our own ship turned against us…
我们的船竟然开始攻击我们…
…tangling the crew，wrapping around 'em like snakes.
…绳索缠住船员 像蛇一样绞着他们
And wrapping around me leg.
也缠住了我的腿
But me arms were free and me sword was to hand.
但是我的手还能动 手里握着剑
I am the master of me ship，not Blackbeard.
船长是我 不是黑胡子
I am the master of my fate，not Blackbeard.
掌握命运的是我 不是黑胡子
So I did what needed done.
所以我当机立断
I survived.
活下来了
So… you're not after the Fountain.
所以…你不是来找不老泉的
I care not for King George or tavern yarns
管他什么乔治国王
that give hope for a healed limb.
还有什么能治伤腿的偏方
But I'd give my left arm for a chance at Blackbeard.
我只想用左手抓住黑胡子报仇
- Not your right？- I need me good arm
- 为什么不是右手？ - 我要右手
to drive my poisoned blade through his heart.
把淬了毒液的刀子刺进他的心脏
I'll see you get the chance，mate.
我会帮你的 兄弟
The prisoner's escaping.
犯人逃了
He's escaping！Fan out！Find him！
他逃了！快分头去抓他！
Go！Go！
快！快！
Hold your fire！I want him alive！
别开枪！我要抓活的！
I figured that was the signal.
我觉得那就是信号
- Go！Prepare to move out！- The enemy is soon upon us.
- 快！准备出击！ - 敌人正在逼近我们
I'm sorry about the chalices，Jack，but I've an appointment to keep.
圣杯的事对不住了 杰克 我有约在先
- I'll not be going back。- No need.
- 不会回来了 - 没什么对不住的
- Shall we have a drink？- We'll drink at the Fountain.
- 一起喝一杯？ - 去不老泉喝吧
How is it we can never meet without you pointing something at me？
什么时候你能不一见面就拿东西指着我？
You brought the chalices，Sparrow？
圣杯拿来了 斯派罗？
Aye。Oi！
对！
- I see you brought a friend。- I did.
- 你带了个朋友 - 没错
And the one-legged man，he is near。Aye？
那个独腿男人就在附近 对吧？
Aye.
对
Now…
呃…
Before I go just handing them over，I do have one or two conditions.
要我交出圣杯 有一两个条件
- Name them。- Firstly，
- 说 - 首先
I'll be having me compass back。No，no，that's secondly.
把我的罗盘还我 哦不对 这是其次
Firstly，upon your word，
首先 你要保证
you will bring no harm to Angelica.
你不会伤害安吉莉卡
I'll make no vows to the likes of you，Sparrow.
虽然我不屑对你这种人发誓 斯派罗
But it costs me nothing to admit
不过我也没什么损失
that she was never in harm's way.
我本来就不会伤害她
Secondly then，priorly firstly，
那就先谈其次
I will be having me compass back.
罗盘还我
Please？I do deserve it.
还我吧？这可是我的
Do you have any idea how difficult it was to catch that filthy pig？
你知道抓住那只臭猪有多难吗？
Not the big one，the four-legged one.
不是大的那个 四条腿的那只
Thank you。And thirdly，Mr。Beard，
谢谢 那么第三 胡子先生
there are times，not very often，
偶尔 虽然次数不多
when I do reflect upon my heinous misdeeds.
我也会反省自己的种种恶行
Chief among them，I note how poorly I have treated Mr。Gibbs，
最差劲的 就要数我一直亏待了吉布斯先生
- my loyal first mate。- Aye！Now you bring it up…
- 我忠心耿耿的大副 - 哈！现在想起我了啊…
Left him to rot in jail，I did。Didn't care.
我把他丢在牢里 毫不关心
Still don't。But，point being，you must let him go free.
虽然我现在也不关心 但是我想说 你一定要放他自由
- Is that it？- I think so.
- 就这样？ - 差不多吧
Quick，or the pig runs，and good luck getting those chalices.
快点 要是猪跑了 看你怎么拿圣杯
Jack，if it's all the same to you，I'd be just as…
杰克 如果你觉得没差 我可就…
Done.
成交
Release the swine.
把猪放了
Perhaps，if you don't mind，I could tag along with you folk for a…
不介意的话 我愿意跟着你们…
This will lead you to freedom，mate.
它会带你找到自由 兄弟
I could have swore it was somewhere right around here.
我发誓不老泉就在这附近
We must not stop.
我们不能停下来
Dead end.
死胡同
Dead。End.
Dead end.
死胡同
Jack，I'm starting to think you don't know where you're going.
杰克 我开始怀疑你根本不知道路
It is not the destination so much as the journey，they say.
人们都说 过程比结果重要
Chalices，if you please.
麻烦把圣杯给我
Stand back.
退后
Jack…
杰克…
…have you ever，in fact…
你到底有没有…
…seen with your own eyes… the Fountain of Youth？
亲眼见到过…不老泉？
I'm sorry，could you repeat the question，please？
不好意思 你能再问一遍么？
Quartermaster.
舵手
No，no！
别！别！
Wait，wait！Wait.
等一下 等一下
「Aqua… de Vida.」
“生命…之水”
Master Scrum…
斯克拉姆先生…
- …do you mind？- Squire？
- 帮个忙？ - 这样？
So beautiful.
真美
Sparrow，I'll be the first to taste those waters.
斯派罗 我要第一个喝这泉水
Father.
父亲
The one-legged man.
独腿人
- You brought him here。- Would I do that？
- 是你带他来这的 - 我干嘛要这么做？
Edward Teach！
爱德华·蒂奇！
For crimes committed on the high seas，
鉴于你在公海犯下的累累罪行
by the authority granted me by His Majesty the King…
国王陛下授权于我…
…and with a goodly amount of personal satisfaction…
…外加我们之间颇为深重的个人恩怨…
…I hereby place you in the custody of the court，
…我在此依法拘捕你
and declare you to be my prisoner.
并宣布你是我的罪犯
My trick's out，is that it？
我没戏唱了 是吧？
Such crimes do include，but are not limited to，piracy，treason，
你犯的罪行包括 海上掠夺 叛国
murder，torture of the most heinous sort，
谋杀 施酷刑
including the brutal theft of one used，twisted，hairy right leg.
还有残忍夺走他人右腿罪
You… dare face this sword？
你…还敢面对这把剑？
This far away from your ship？Aye.
在离你的船这么远的地方 当然敢
Aye。That be the cold breath of fate I feel down my nape.
好 尽管我可能命不久矣
But I'll have one last fight，by God.
但我也要决一死战 以上帝的名义！
Kill 'em all！
杀了他们！
Hang on a minute.
等一下
I just… I just need to understand something.
我…我们先把话说明白
Right，so，you will fight against them，
那么 你们要打他们
they will fight against you.
他们要打你们
All on account of him wanting to kill him？
只因为他想要杀了他？
Where is the sense？Exactly.
没道理啊！是吧
I say，let them fight each other while we lay back，
要我说 就让他们单打独斗 我们就坐边上
watch，have a drink，place some wagers！
喝喝小酒 打打小赌 看看好戏！
Aye.
好
- Kill 'em！- No quarter！
- 杀了他们！ - 一个不留！
Get off me！
滚开！
Scrum，the chalices！
斯克拉姆 圣杯！
And the tear！Follow！
拿着眼泪！跟我来！
Fight！
杀啊！
Hand it over。The tear。There's a good lad.
把眼泪交出来 乖
I'm more afraid of her than I am of you.
比起你我更怕她
Hand it over。There's a good lad.
把眼泪交出来 乖
- The chalices，if you please。- Sorry，Jack.
- 不介意的话 把圣杯给我 - 抱歉 杰克
I told you，I need years。And now，yours will do.
我说过 我需要寿命 你的就可以
Scrum！
斯克拉姆！
Syrena…
瑟琳娜…
Oh God，you will not take her.
哦上帝 不要带走她
If you have taken her，you will give her back.
就算你已带走她 也请让她活过来
Give her back…
让她活过来…
Give her back，please。Please.
活过来…求你了…
I expected fate to put up more of a fight，eh？
我还以为命运之神会再眷顾你们一些的
I will not have that smile on your face as I strike you down.
杀了你 看你还能不能笑得出来
Take a gander，Edward Teach.
看后面 爱德华·提切
This land is hereby forever claimed in the glorious name
这片土地永远属于
of His Majesty King George…
尊敬的乔治国王陛下…
Someone make a note of that man's bravery.
我们会铭记他的英勇
Sedrita，the chalices，por favor.
小姐 请交出圣杯
Only God can grant eternal life，not this pagan water.
只有上帝才能赐予生命永恒 而非这异教的泉水
Men，destroy this profane temple！
摧毁这亵渎上帝的庙宇！
The Fountain！
不老泉！
You are a fool.
你这个蠢货
You seek in this place what only faith can provide.
你所追求的 只有信仰才能赐予你
Faith？In faith，there is light enough to see
信仰？信仰之光不足以照亮
but darkness enough to blind.
我眼前的黑暗
What devilry is this？
这是干什么？
- For the Pearl。- What have you done？
- 为黑珍珠号报仇 - 你干了什么？
Angelica！Don't！It's poison！
安吉莉卡！别碰！有毒！
I'm not such the fool to take on Blackbeard
要对付黑胡子还不耍一些卑劣的小手段
without a little venomous advantage.
我还没那么笨
Jack！
杰克！
I claim Blackbeard's ship and crew，
我宣布 用黑胡子的船和船员
and this sword，payment for my missing limb！
以及这把剑 作为我断腿的补偿！
Hang on！Pull！
坚持住！拉！
Do not waste my tear.
别浪费我的眼泪
Drink this。This one has the tear.
喝了这个 这里面有眼泪
- You must drink the other。- No！
- 你得喝另一杯 - 不！
I cannot save you both。One of you must sacrifice.
我救不了你们两个 必须有一个人牺牲
You take it，Father，for your soul.
你喝这个 父亲 为了你的灵魂
Captain Teach，she's dying。You must save your daughter.
蒂奇船长 她快死了 你得救你女儿
This one takes life？
这杯会夺走生命？
This one has the tear and gives life？
这杯有眼泪的能获得永生？
Aye，hurry！
是 快点！
Angelica… Save me，my child.
安吉莉卡…救救我 孩子
No.
不要
I love you，Father.
我爱你 父亲
Wait a minute.
等一下
In fact，it might have been the other way around.
其实 我可能说错了
This cup had the tear，that one had the other bit.
这杯里有眼泪 另一杯是泉水
Trickster！
骗子！
- Devil！- Father！
- 魔鬼！ - 父亲！
You bastard！How could you？
混蛋！你怎么能这样！
Your father saved you.
你父亲救了你
Perhaps his soul is now redeemed，eh？
也许这样他的灵魂就能得到救赎了
You are hurt.
你受伤了
In body only.
只是肉体的伤而已
My mind is at peace… because of you.
我的心很平静…因为你
- Me？- Yes.
- 我？ - 是
I was lost.
我曾迷失了自己
The wind，the tides…
海风 浪潮…
…they ought to renew a man's faith.
…本能令人重拾信仰
But for me，only you.
但对我来说 只有你能
Philip，I can save you.
菲利普 我可以救你
You need only ask.
只要你求我
- I seek but one thing。- What is that？
- 我只求一件事 - 什么？
Forgiveness.
原谅我
If not for me，you would never have been captured.
如果不是我 你不会被抓
Ask.
求我
Forgive me？
原谅我？
I hate you.
我恨你
The bloke who saved your life？
我可救了你哎
The years I possess，stolen from my own father！
我的生命 是从我亲生父亲那偷来的！
I only helped Blackbeard do what any father should have done.
我只是帮黑胡子做了一个父亲该做的事
You are cruel and ignorant.
你又冷血又无知
One pistol，one shot.
一把手枪 一发子弹
To kill myself before I starve？
让我在饿死前自杀？
There's no trusting you，love.
我信不过你 亲爱的
Besides，this is a well-traveled trade route.
另外 这是一条商路
You can signal a passing ship.
你可以向过路的船只求救
Or you can just bite the proverbial bullet，as it were.
要么就扣扳机自杀 随你便
And how will I get free of these bonds？
那我怎么给自己松绑？
You broke free of your bonds half an hour ago，
你半小时前就挣脱了
waiting for the precise moment to pounce.
就等着好时机来攻击我
Admit it，Jack.
承认吧 杰克
- You still love me。- If you had a sister and a dog，
- 你还爱我 - 如果你还有个妹妹和小狗
I'd choose the dog.
我会选小狗
Treasure！There is a chest with jewels！
宝藏！我有一箱珠宝！
Jewels with the power to rule the wind and tide！
足够让你称霸海上！
- You're making that up！- Wait…
- 你就扯吧！ - 等等…
I am with child。Yours.
我有了 是你的
I don't recall that we ever had…
我可不记得我们有过…
- You were drunk！- I've actually never been that drunk.
- 你喝多了！ - 我还不至于那么多
Wait！
等等！
There is something I want to say to you.
我有话要跟你说
Something I wanted to say from the moment we first met.
我第一次见到你时就想说了
Go on，then.
那就 说吧
I love you.
我爱你
As do I.
我也是
Always have。Always will.
一直爱你 永远爱你
I gotta go.
我得闪了
Jack！
杰克！
This is not over！
还没完呢！
Jack！
杰克！
Missed！
偏啦！
The Revenge is mine.
安妮女王复仇号 是我的了！
Sir…
长官…
We found this below decks.
在船舱里找到的
All hands！Ply to windward！
全体船员！迎风航行！
Get cracking，ye blooming cockroaches！
快干活 你们这些臭虫！
The Crown served me well.
王室待我不薄
But now，by the gods of sea and sky…
但在海神和苍天的见证下…
…make way for Tortuga！
驶向托儿图加港吧！
Gibbs，you filthy，besotted shellback，you made it！
吉布斯 你这个死鬼 你成功了！
Aye！
没错！
And I trust we managed a profit
我看我们可以合开个公司了
- from our joint enterprise？- Feast your eyes.
- 准能挣大钱 - 睁大眼睛看吧
The compass led me straight and true.
罗盘直接把我带到那地方
What of Blackbeard's men guarding the ship？
黑胡子的守卫呢？
I employed the selfsame maneuver we perfected in New Guinea.
我用了在新几内亚学的那招防御术
Seemed a shame to leave an entire fleet behind.
不把整个舰队都带来就白瞎了
Shame indeed.
确实白瞎
I hate that monkey.
我恨这猴子
So，the Pearl… Any idea how to get her out？
那你知道怎么把黑珍珠号弄出来么？
We shall need a crossbow，an hourglass，three goats.
需要十字弓 沙漏和三只山羊
One of us must learn to play the trumpet whilst the other one goes like this…
一个人吹小号 另一个跳大神…
- I know a man with a goat。- Good。I can go like this.
- 我认识一个人有山羊 - 太好了 我可以来这个
Jack，I have to ask…
杰克 我很想知道…
You had the chalices，the water，the tear…
你有圣杯 泉水和人鱼眼泪…
You could have lived maybe forever.
你本可以永生的
The Fountain does test you，Gibbs.
这就是不老泉的考验 吉布斯
But better to not know which moment may be your last.
最好还是别知道自己的死期
Every morsel of your entire being
这样你每时每刻
alive to the infinite mystery of it all.
都在探索生命的神秘
And who's to say I won't live forever，eh？
谁说我不会永生呢？
Discoverer of the Fountain of Youth.
不老泉的发现者
I have no say in it，Gibbs.
这可不是我吹的 吉布斯
It's a pirate's life for me.
我就喜欢当海盗
Savvy？
懂了吧？